this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at sc-radio.net
SE radio is brought to you by the IEEE
computer Society by IEEE software
Magazine online at computer.org software
[Music]
hello and welcome to software
engineering radio this is your host
nikhil and today I have the pleasure of
welcoming Ari mankali Ori is a senior
vice president of engineering at equilus
a leading Cloud security startup prior
to his current position he served as the
VP of research and development at the
same company for nearly four years
Audi's professional strengths include
cyber security it operations and
architecture with a particular
Proficiency in embedded Linux Internet
Protocol Suites debugging and
multi-threading and Unix before joining
akelex Ori held significant roles at
several major companies he was a
director of software development at
Drive Nets and a manager of software
development at both Amazon web services
in Germany and Compass networks Ori
holds a masters and a bachelor's degree
in computer science from the barilan
University in Israel
today we'll be talking to Ori about
Secrets management using distributed
fragment cryptography so welcome to the
show already is there anything that I
missed out in the bio that you would
like to add no I think it was pretty
accurate and thank you for hosting me
today uh Nick Hill I'm delighted to be
here in this show
and answer questions related to Secrets
management and talk about cryptography
and I think that interests you perfect
Okay cool so let's just jump right in
right so we said that the title of the
show is Secrets management and let's
start from there so could you explain
what secrets are and why are we calling
them Secrets versus passwords versus
keys or whatever other terms that we use
for these kind of things yeah I think
it's a good starting point because there
there is a lot of confusion around
terminology and the differences between
keys and passwords and secrets typically
we call Secrets any kind of sensitive
information that is used mostly for
authentication by applications so for
example if you have some piece of code
written in whatever language Java
anything uh similar to that and your
piece of code needs to authenticate to a
remote service it can be a database or
another service I don't know kubernetes
cluster shows anything of that nature
then it needs to identify itself the
application needs to identify itself in
order to be authenticated and later on
be authorized to access remote Services
historically this sensitive information
was stored in insecure places like a
configuration file or even inside the
code even hard-coded
so all those types of sensitive
information we bundle under the name
Secrets passwords is the term that we
normally use for a human access so very
similar to password managers if you if
you know a lot of browser extensions
mobile applications Etc
so all types of human access is
considered again terminology wise for
passwords
and keys we normally call Keys anything
that use cryptographic is can be
symmetric is
or asymmetric is that they're used for
different purposes normally symmetric
keys are used for encryption typically
not just
and asymmetric keys are mostly used for
signing operations and that's the
distinction between the different names
but eventually they're all part of the
same word of uh so yeah it's the same
world of sensitive information that
needs to be I like the way you've
differentiated so Secrets can be
primarily looked at from the lens of
okay this is usually something that you
want to look at from an application a
machine to machine interaction
perspective versus passwords are usually
when there is a human involved so moving
on to the next word which is management
so can you talk about Secrets management
why it is important yeah I think
everything at the end relates to scale
and let me elaborate what I mean by that
imagine that you have like a single
application that's the only thing this
application is doing is just connecting
to a database so we have a single
application with a single secret and
it's not too hard to manage you can even
wrap it in a way that would be
considered somewhat secured in the sense
that the secret the sensitive
information will be encrypted but it's
just one and now imagine that you have a
large organization with I don't know
hundreds of thousands of services
applications the modern microservices
exactly exactly scaling out like if
you're running on top of kubernetes you
have tons of that and now you have
different kinds of applications that
need permissions to different kinds of
secrets so it's not just one it's
millions of Secrets and you need to have
some kind of access policy like how
would you differentiate between one
application to another between one human
to another
you need to have some kind of auditing
right you need to be able to see which
application accessed which secret or
which human access which Secret in order
to be able to retrospect and remediate
in case of uh security hazards Etc
so this is becoming a big problem like
it's not enough just to protect the
secret using some kind of an encryption
key you need a system to facilitate the
access to secrets to configure different
kinds of authentication methods
different ways to authenticate to the
platforms and and be able to fetch
secrets and configure them
you need a good and solid access policy
or access roses we call them because we
implemented row base Access Control
you need to be able to integrate with
external identity providers so you will
have a single sign-on authentication to
the platform audit log that can be
edited and searched and maybe even can
be forwarded to existing log systems
because many organizations have their
own log systems may it be Splunk or
syslog or elasticsearch or you name it
and in many cases you also need some
kind of visualization for Auditors like
if you have a ciso or security officers
in the organization they would like to
have a visual view or overview should I
say about the activities about access
Etc so all that requires is and even in
the basic case also right you probably
want to have keys to you need to be able
to change the key you need to be able to
delete the key add new keys when people
leave the organization you want to
refresh the keys etc etc right 100 right
it's it's the life cycle of a key or a
secret maintaining versions of keys be
able as you mentioned to create new ones
to delete existing ones Etc update them
so obviously this is a lot of things but
there are existing systems to manage a
lot of data right so data management
that's pretty much every business
application you can you do a crud
application it is create read update
delete you can do this for a thing so
what are the unique challenges that
Secrets management faces that makes it
kind of unique that doesn't kind of
allow it to be fitting into a regular
application management flow yeah I would
say that not every data every type of
data is classified as sensitive so you
could store I don't know this different
kinds of string you don't necessarily
have to go and encrypt them uh depending
on the use case so protecting Secrets is
a mission uh which is with more
responsibilities in terms of security
because potential hackers and malicious
users would want to find those Secrets
inside organization in order to get
access to other types of systems and
then do what we call the lateral
movement starting to expand their
knowledge about the organization about
sensitive information so it's a good
Target for malicious activity to learn
about the organization so they need to
be protected in an extra secure fashion
and obviously you can write your own
layer on top of a traditional data
storage like databases Etc but then it
means that you need to somehow reinvent
the wheel every company every
organization would have to go had an
invest time engineering time and Define
the security standards and be complied
with certain security certifications
Etc and that's something that
organization would prefer not to invest
their business in it yeah it's it's not
a core competency right it's not
something that they do day to day and
it's probably something that they would
want to pay for
great so I think that's a good overview
of Secrets and why we manage Secrets
maybe we can move on to the second part
of it which is maybe can you give us an
introduction into distributed fragments
cryptography and you know give us a
higher level overview of what that is
sure so that's probably the foundation
of a keyless that's where I a kid has
started about five years ago it was uh
an idea that came from one of our
Founders our CTO his name is Rafael
Angel and he was working at the time for
a fintech company
and he realized that one of the things
that the basic question that people need
to ask themselves is not how data is
protected because encryption algorithms
are with us for many many years the
algorithms are well known everything is
is considered to be secured but the main
question is where do you store the key
that is used for the protection for the
encryption the common answer in many
cases like you have the silky or the
root key is stored in an HSM Hardware
secure model which is technically a
physical box a physical machine with a
certain set of security requirements
it's going through certifications Etc I
seem to remember it was something that
Intel had introduced right as part of
the CPU architecture sgx I think it was
cool that's something particular for
CPUs as you mentioned but this box that
I'm talking about is something that is
it can be like a pizza box or a physical
machine it's more of a system not just a
box I can also tell you that cloud
providers are offering that as a service
so you have Cloud HSM Solutions first of
all they're very expensive
and secondly because of their Hardware
nature they're not easily scaled you
need a different Hardware box for every
secret so the idea that he came up with
is instead of trying to protect this
root key this initial key in some kind
of a physical location that would be
hard to penetrate this is the Assumption
of using an HSM instead of that let's
not use any key in any single location
so he decided to manage the keys in a
different way and he built the DFC
technology this is our own proprietary
patented technology it stands for
distributed fragments cryptography so
instead of having a single key in a
single location in memory or persistent
storage doesn't matter of a specific
application instead of that you have X
number of fragments
and those fragments are composing one
logical key but this key is never been
brought together so the fragments are
remaining at those locations physical
locations different servers different
regions even and you can use the key but
you cannot get the full key as a whole
not even in memory that's interesting
because I think that's I think the
unique difference between you and say
secret sharing right if you want to do
like multi-signature kind of a deal
where you have uh you're talking about
some of your secrets right secret
sharing or other these kind of
cryptographic methods which I am aware
of where basically you have this idea of
you have multiple keys with multiple
people that need to be combined to get
access to a secret door and and so this
is different from that correct which
music we're sharing at some point in
time as part of the algorithm that you
combine the fragments together or the
pieces together and do some kind of
cryptographic operation and then later
on you can split the key again or to do
whatever with the data with a keyless
that's not the case because when as part
of the algorithm we're not bringing the
fragments outside of their location okay
so they remain in their location
we have a microservice representing each
one of the fragment managers we call
them
and there is some kind of an algorithm
that allows us to communicate with this
microservice and get a request served
for each and every operation so one
other thought that comes to mind then is
that okay so you have this key fragments
distributed across multiple places what
happens if one of them goes down is
there a requirement that all of them
should be up for the purposes of the
signing or for the purpose of the
functioning of this cryptography or is
it kind of like with threshold
signatures that's another technology
that's similar in multi-party
computation you just need K of n right
you just need maybe if it's a three five
signatures you just need you can say I
linked only three of them in order to do
the encryption on the decryption is it
similar for DFC not internet so for DFC
it's not allowing you to use only subset
or k of N Out of the fragments however
for resiliency we have designed our
system to replicate fragments to
different Geographic locations so
instead of having just one instance in
one region of the fragments we replicate
it to at least two other locations one
of them is inside the region so another
availability Zone and another one is to
another region so the likelihood that
both the same region and another region
would not be available at the same time
is lower
but you still need N Out of n so you
have more places to get the access to
the N fragments but you still need
access to all of them
so you'll still need access to all of
them how do you actually handle
refreshing so when I refresh a key or if
I want to change the key because
somebody left the organization for
whatever reason I want to refresh the
key does it mean that all the fragments
need to be refreshed or is this kind of
something that happens independently how
does that work yeah so it's a great
question so in terms of terminologic and
I know that a lot of terminology is
involved in in our talk so we call what
you just described rotate key the reason
that we call it this way because we also
have an interesting refresh mechanism
and I will touch on that in just a bit
as part of our patent scheme rotating a
key essentially means that you create a
whole new key and just create it in a
new version okay so we create a set of n
new fragments that represents this new
key it just it's associated with the
previous one in terms of the ID of the
key it's known to have a succeeder of
that previous key Etc we also allow the
administrators to configure a periodic
rotation so if they want let's say once
a week or once a month or once a year to
have a new version of the key that's
also doable the refresh mechanism that I
talked about it's another interesting
part of our patent because you can
assume that you have let's say that we
have n locations five locations for
example that holds the fragments and if
I'm a malicious hacker and I know that I
need to have access to this logical key
in order to be able to decrypt all the
data so I have infinite amount of time I
can try to hack a certain location and
then after a while try to get access to
another fragment and another fragment
then slowly and gradually maybe get
access to all the N fragments if if
that's possible we have implemented the
mechanism that basically change the
mathematical value of each fragment in a
synchronous way without changing the
overall sum of the key so let's imagine
that the key was no no one thousand in
bits whatever doesn't matter
the fact that we changed the value of
the fragments did not change the sum of
the key so you can still use it
seamlessly and we do that in a
synchronous fashion because this
operation needs to be coordinated
otherwise it will change the value of
the key and we do it periodically
without even like completely seamless
from the user's perspective okay so it's
part of the algorithm itself it's part
of the algorithm yes yeah okay and the
value the big value of it isn't it now
it's not enough to get one fragment
after the other now you have to do that
simultaneously and that's much harder
for a malicious user to do because as I
mentioned there are different locations
doing that at once is very difficult
task right okay cool that sounds really
powerful so does this mean that the
algorithm or this key basically that
comes up with is simply a large
numerical value not like a YouTube ID
where you have num numbers and it's a
cryptographic key it's a cryptographic
yeah it's identical yeah it's a bit
value it's identical to any other key in
terms of length and structure and shape
that is generated locally like even
everything is pure standard standard
cryptography we are using standard
encryption algorithms signing algorithms
everything is pure standard so what are
the standard cryptographic algorithms on
which this is based for symmetric is we
support AES which is probably the most
common standards in two different
flavors and two different sizes so 128
bits and 256 Sav and gcn and for
asymmetric similarly to that we support
RSA from 1K length to 4K at the moment
and we also support the different flavor
so we basically have some kind of a seal
key for any type of other Keys like
elliptic curve and other algorithms that
are not supported yet by DFC
so we basically protect this key using
another DFC key so it's it's not
limiting you to use any kind of
encryption or signing algorithm so we
talked about DFC we talked about that
it's a underlying it's just a standard
key it can be used for public key
private key and symmetric as a symmetric
we also talked about the fact that you
have different fragments in different
places correct so does the fragment kind
of all reside on your machines or is it
kind of like a combination where uh the
some of the fragments has to be on the
client and then it has to be on a server
it's a flexible kind of a thing yeah
it's a great point because I think one
of the main concerns mostly for our
large corporates and Enterprises is
who has access to my sensitive
information that's a question that
they're being asked a lot as part of
security and certifications and
compliance reasons Etc
and today with many cloud-based
Solutions
they need to somewhat trust the vendor
that their data is safe if the vendor
has access to the key it means that they
also have access to the data so because
of the nature of our algorithm or
patented technology
and the fact that we can create as many
fragments as we want we allow our
customers to have an optional fragment
that is created locally to the
customer's environment and it's also a
part of the key so it's yet another
fragment of the key so let's say that
you have just for the example five
fragments so maybe four of them are
created and stored and managed by us by
a keyless on the on our Cloud
subscription and one of them is residing
locally to the customer environment
where a us a keyless we don't have
access to it this means that all the
cryptographic operations for any case
will always happen from the customer's
environment simply because without
having access to all the N fragments as
we discussed before then you could not
do any kind of operation so the
operations are happening locally the
customer has full privacy and access to
his data in a way that no third party
including a keyless can access their
data that's a huge yeah so but the
downside of that obviously is that now
again it depends on the client being up
all the time right so if there is a
network partition between the client and
a keyless then your secrets I mean you
will not be able to sign another because
the client is down for example right
it's not entirely how we implemented it
and I I can share two main concerns one
of them is what you just mentioned but
the other one is how to facilitate it to
many different kinds of clients right
you can imagine that you have different
applications and now how do I bring to
this application yeah and that's
becoming like an operational hustle so
what we've designed is to have a
centralized component to the customer's
environment which we call a keyless
Gateway
as the name implies it means that the
traffic to retrieve secrets and to
create secrets and to modify them in any
basically any operation to our platform
is going through this Gateway and this
Gateway is the one storing and managing
the fragment it requires only outgoing
traffic no inbound traffic is required
no need to modify your network topology
Etc this allows you to have a seamless
encryption decryption signing operations
through the Gateway without getting
access physically to the customer
fragment another advantage that covers
the the topic that you raised is about
network connectivity what happens if for
some reason the customer is unable to
communicate with the backend service Etc
we allow optionally to have caching
service on the Gateway and basically
storing the secrets on the Gateway in
two different modes one of them is
called the opportunistic caching which
means that only if you requested it
before then and you will have access to
it and the second one is proactive
caching which means that we store all
the secrets that the client has access
to in memory of course in a protected
fashion but in case there is an
temporary Network outage or something
like that you can still get access to
your secrets you can still perform
operations to your internal workload and
applications in a seamless manner so
your application would not even notice
that cool so moving on to just wanted to
also lightly touch about the question of
Standards obviously this is cryptography
cryptography is usually there are
standards bodies what are the
certifications that DHC has and what do
you think are they significant do you
feel that you can share them sure for
sure I agree with you regarding
standards I I think that nobody wants to
invent the wheel in that aspect of
cryptography there is a lot of mileage a
lot of eyes a lot of experience that was
gained throughout the years Akitas as a
company started from the very beginning
to do different kinds of certifications
so we are shocked to type 2 certified
ESO 27701 27001 and we also have fips
140-2 certification that is the security
certification by the US nist which is
considered pretty much the the strongest
and well-known standard in the industry
for that I think that we're one of the
few vendors that are certified for fips
140-2 for Secrets management for other
Realms key management and HSM that's
very common for Secrets management it's
not yet very common so this is one of
our differentiation between our
competition I think that's a good
overview of EFC and its capabilities
let's move on to a obviously from the
application perspective so suppose if I
am a client and I have a existing
business I don't know it's a standard
e-commerce business how would I kind of
adopt DFC I signed up with the aquilas
what is available is there any kind of
guide so what is the method by which I
can integrate with aculus into my
architecture and maybe we could kind of
discuss the simple architecture like
e-commerce architecture just as an
example so people can understand I think
one of our main objectives is to make
our platform easy to consume easy to use
okay and easy means that our customers
need to invest as little as possible to
integrate with it in different use cases
it wouldn't be like a major task of
onboarding with us from an operational
perspective so we support a lot of
interfaces when I say interfaces that
can be human interfaces like web UI
through your favorite browser it can be
a CLI command line interface both for
humans that prefer to work from the
terminal from the shell or for small
scripts and applications that they would
like to execute this CLI as well as
restful API
sdks in many programming languages
including not just Java python go
c-sharp Ruby and many many other types
of programming languages and a lot of
plugins that can be used directly from
devops tools as part of your devops tool
chain it can be CI CD platforms the most
common platforms that you can imagine we
support large variety configuration
management tools orchestrations of
different kinds so you basically can
choose which interface is the most
suitable for your needs for example if
you have a homegrown application
something you develop in-house then it's
most likely you would prefer to work
with the SDK if it's an application that
was created by third party and you have
little to no control of it you would
probably want to use one of our plugins
to I know kubernetes or to inject the
secrets seamlessly to the application
without an explicit API call so
typically usually businesses now are in
one of the main clouds right it'll be
either in AWS or in Google cloud or
Azure do you have plugins to these three
as well I mean can I take my AWS IAM
system and just use that into a keyless
and how does that actually work yeah so
I'm decoupling between the interface or
the way to communicate with the platform
and the authentication method how the
client identifies itself between the two
so what you discussed is about the
authentication we support all the three
major Cloud providers to use their
native IAM or identity of the machine in
order to authenticate to a killer so for
example you mentioned AWS so you have a
workload running on ec2 for example you
can use your AWS IAM to authenticate to
Achilles seamlessly without having any
kind of initial Secret or secret zero in
many cases it's called same for Asia or
ID and gcp IAM and if you're running on
kubernetes you can use your kubernetes
identity uh to authenticate to Achilles
jot authentication it's very common for
CI CD platforms today and many other
authentication methods we have about a
dozen different kinds of authentication
methods most of them are done seamlessly
relying on the underlying infrastructure
signature and that's considered very
secure so to make this a little bit more
kind of clear in my head so imagine I'm
running a kubernetes application right
so it's a e-commerce site it is a nginx
web server there's a order management I
don't know python server back-end and
then there is a database a postgres
database right running on this
kubernetes cluster I'm using kubernetes
secrets for the secret management very
basic and I'm kind of buying this on to
aws's container management solution
forget its name so this is mostly
self-managed it's just hosted in AWS
right so we had mentioned that we can
put a Gateway right so would that
actually can you set up the AQ less
Gateway as a Gateway on my internal
kubernetes cluster and then manage the
secrets there what would you recommend
in in for this kind of today yeah the
Gateway is definitely a good choice and
as I mentioned it's running on your
environment on the customer's
environment it can run it's basically
provided as a container container image
so you can run it either as a standalone
container for example it can be a Docker
on a VM or it can be it's more
recommended actually to be run on some
kind of orchestration ECS eks anything
of that nature to allow easy Auto
scaling to meet your needs and also to
have a built-in monitoring and high
availability in case one of the
containers for some reason goes down
then there will be some kind of
monitoring and be able to spin up a new
container as a replacement this Gateway
can run it's mostly typical to have one
per Network segment so if if you go
again to the cloud architecture is very
common to have different kinds of vpcs
that each VPC has access to network
resources inside of APC so you can and
spin up a Gateway pair of vehicles
exactly to serve the workload inside the
VPC and coming back to your question
then you can use the cloud native IAM to
authenticate through the gateway to
Achilles cloud and consume Secrets as a
replacement for kubernetes Secrets or
any other Secret store that you use
today right right and that's where the
SDK comes in so I would just write the
python SDK to directly bypass kubernetes
that's one of the option that's one of
the options to use the python SDK
another option to do the seamlessly is
to use one of our kubernetes plugins and
we support a large variety the most
common one the most is the mutating web
hook which is basically a pod that is
installed on your cluster that receives
events whenever a new deployment is
taking place and then based on
annotations it can inject either an
innate container or a sidecar to your
existing deployment and this will allow
us to fetch Secrets seamlessly to your
application so the application is not
aware that the secret perspected where
we are and then you can provide it
either as an environment variable to
your application or as a mounted virtual
file system in both cases it happens
inside the Pod so it's considered
application Level decryption so it's not
something it's visible outside of the
Pod or an hcd or any anywhere else so
it's very secure and it's most
importantly it's seamless okay so if you
used to create secrets from a file or
from environment variable you continue
to do that without knowing that the
security level just took a step up so
actually that that's an interesting
point so since in the sidecar this is
you've got the side gun you've injected
it does the algorithm run inside the
sidecar or is it it kind of still it
runs inside everything as I mentioned
everything is related to cryptography
encryption decryption all that is
happening on the customer's environment
so basically we built a small container
image minimal with low footprint that
does this algorithm inside that
container so then performance becomes no
longer a problem because you're not
worried about the network it's it's
happening inside the site car itself and
another reason it's not considered a big
issue because in many cases the secret
is required for establishing the session
so you need to get access to the secret
in order to connect to the remote
service to the remote database and then
the operations are done in a different
fashion after you authenticate it so
it's not in the critical parts of all
the data path so I think that's a great
example and it kind of helps me thank
you so much it helps me kind of mentally
put in my head okay how would I kind of
integrate this
so we talked about this barriers where
DFC can be I mean a solution Achilles
can be applied are there any places or
are there any business applications
which you would not recommend Achilles
they're kind of like I'm just kind of
going for the negative case so is there
any specific areas that you think that
it's not a great fit so I think that's
it's a matter of where we fit best so
anything that is a modern environment
it's kind of like our Forte mostly Cloud
environments but not just we also
support on-premise environment using our
Gateway because the Gateway needs to
have access to your resources but
environments that are fully arrogapped
are not yet adapted to our solution it's
not that we wouldn't be able to do that
in the future to be able to provide you
the backend services to run on the
customers at the environment that's
technically doable but at the moment we
decided to run as a SAS service running
on our Cloud subscription so
environments that are would not be a
great fit to our solution at this point
right
right okay and so another one that kind
of occurred to me might be like you know
where you have packaged software being
shipped on CDs that run uh independently
or something right where you don't have
to have any kind of network connection
for it to work yeah so it's again coming
down to the aerogact environment
anything that doesn't have a continuous
connectivity to the outside world
doesn't have to be direct by the way so
it can be something like uh the Gateway
can run on some kind of like a DMZ and
then the application needs to have
access to the Gateway and the Gateway is
the one that needs to have outgoing
traffic to our backend Services okay so
it can be indirect also going through
HTTP proxies if you'd like even SSL
inspection if the organization Works in
that manner then it's all supported it's
all doable but fully air gapped it's
still something we do not support what
are the best practices that you would
recommend for Secrets management and the
use of DFC I mean other than obviously
contract and by your solution of course
but even in terms of practices how do I
kind of make sure that I'm doing the
right things we didn't talk about that
but one of the uh biggest features or
most uh Advanced features that the
secrets management has to offer today is
called Just in Time access or in other
words Dynamic Secrets meaning that
instead of having like a username and
password to a database or an API key or
some kind of a token stored on a secret
management platform the risk is that at
some point in time this value may be
exposed to unauthorized person or
unauthorized application
so instead of that the concept is to
generate just-in-time credentials to any
application that you want which would be
ephemeral which means that after a
certain amount of time the administrator
defines the credentials are being
revoked or removed from the remote
systems which means that they are not
long lasting and they also don't require
rotation because they simply disappear
yeah and that's also a in alignment with
the zero standing privileges concept
meaning that at a steady state if nobody
is connected to a remote server or
remote machine they will not be
persistent user specific persistent
identities on any remote system and
that's the ultimate goal I think in
terms of security
secondly it's applying principle of list
privilege meaning that you grant access
based on what the application or human
needs only so if you need access to two
specific secrets that's the permissions
that you need to Define nothing more
nothing less combining the two together
it's bringing a very high standard of
security least privilege plus just in
time so limited amount of time so even
if somebody was at a specific point in
time in your application and had access
to your CI CD pipeline or had access to
your application memory at some point in
time there will still nothing that they
can grab and use Elsewhere for a long
duration of time right it'll be kind of
like a ephemeral thing let me ask you so
if you take that back so isn't that
something that is it's a best practice
and I agree but isn't it a little hard
to kind of implement in practice like
for example with a database connection
databases are set up for whatever reason
I guess Legacy reasons this concept of a
username and a password with a
long-running kind of session ideas does
a keyless have any kind of solution that
handles that or uh yeah we're not we're
not modifying the way that the systems
are used to work today so there is
programmatic way to create a user on a
database oh yeah okay so that would be
something that the client would have to
build in order to form not necessarily
again not necessarily if you go let's
let's talk about the use case again with
the kubernetes cluster that we inject to
a specific pod something seamlessly okay
and let's say that this part is
something that runs for a short duration
doing some certain set of jobs and then
terminates and then spins up again and
so on in that case you can simply inject
instead of injecting persistent use
element password you can simply inject
just in time credentials that's a great
fit for that use case and even if it's
something that happens let's say like a
long lasting service that once in a
while needs access to it imagine that
you have of our sidecar part of your
deployment and then every I don't know
five minutes just renews this just in
time user or rotates the password of
that user and the only responsibility
for your application is to be able to
re-read the file reload the file again
using a programmatic interface or just
periodically or even event driven like
using something like some mechanism like
I notify or something that tells you
when the file is is modified and then
you can reload the credentials and
that's taking it to the next level again
without modifying the actual software
the piece of code that consumed the
secret and use it from the application
perspective from your application
perspective it's just a username and
password you don't know those are
ephemeral or those are temporary and
about to be deleted very shortly very
cool yeah yeah I think that's a great
use case for this
keeping an eye on the time we've had a
pretty good discussion about dfce its
application in an example application
and what AQ less rings and what keyless
Secrets management is is there anything
that we did not cover that you think we
should also cover in this episode yeah
just a few points because I think that a
lot of our listeners today are thinking
themselves hey I do have secrets
Management in my kubernetes cluster and
I do have secrets Management in my CI CD
platforms Etc why not use them it's
already there it's built in it's most
likely free and then the answer that I
give for them is maintaining those
secret silos so to say is is another
task mostly because each one of them has
different security standards I think
it's a known fact that for kubernetes
it's not the secrets by default are not
even encrypted they're base64 encoded
and for others you need to configure
different kinds of access policies
sometimes you have the same secrets in
different stores and now you need to
synchronize them sometimes you need to
like to have an holistic view a global
view of all the activity what's going on
you need audit logs this is something
that is not often received by those
secret stores so having a lot of secret
stores and secret silos is just another
fancy way for storing the or maintaining
the secret sprawl one of the benefits of
using a keyless and other Secrets
management centralized Secrets
management is to have a centralized
place a single source of tools that
holds the data protects it have disaster
recovery and high availability standards
and procedures and that's again a huge
benefit to large organizations yeah
better visibility and more control just
kind of key yeah so that's great so yeah
I just wanted to take the opportunity to
thank you Ori this was a great chat and
I think we had some very interesting
insights and very valuable insights into
Secrets management so thank you once
again thank you very much it was a big
pleasure to be hosted by you I enjoyed
it it was fun so thanks again and look
forward to hear uh more episodes in your
show absolutely thank you
thanks for listening to SC radio an
educational program brought to you by
Tripoli software magazine for more about
the podcast including other episodes
visit our website at sc-radio dot net
feedback you can comment on each episode
on the website or reach us on LinkedIn
Facebook Twitter or through our slack
Channel at SC radio dot slack.com you
can also email us at team sc.radio.net
this and all other episodes of SC radio
is licensed under created Commons
license 2.5
thanks for listening
[Music]
foreign